Project based learning um it's a fancy
term that simply means that you take
charge of the projects that you're
learning from and the stuff you're going
to do and um this is a continuation of
another video a recommendation from a
rather famous developer TJ Hollow chuk
so make sure you watch that video but
his recommendation uh and the only video
known of him is to take an existing
project and see and see if you can
create recreate it yourself and maybe
you end up with something better those
are the exact words so the idea of
Project based learning is like
fundamental to becoming an autodidact it
means that you take on projects whether
projects that you manufacture for
yourself or someone else has made
manufactured for you but either way when
you're doing project project based
learning it's like I don't know it's
like story problems in school you hated
them but why did you hate them because
you had to really really really
understand the the material and you
would make lots of failures in the
process and you'd have to get you know
you you'd have to to to kind of come
back and do it so um the other thing
about Project based learning is that it
allows you to do projects that are as
close as possible to the real thing and
I'm making another video about this uh
I'll talk about how non Project based
learning or how uh for Education tools
like free code Camp have failed uh so
many people because they do not give the
Hands-On Project based learning that
that that you need in order to truly
Master it in a way that will come back
to you and be available for recall later
when you actually do the thing and you
want to do that thing so as soon as
possible not only do you want to um
start thinking about your own projects
but also
imagining um the kind of projects that
you're going to want to do on the job
and we we talked about that earlier when
in the startup uh you know in the
ignition phase of of the beginner boost
about trying to find those kind of
activities that really you really enjoy
and this is yet another reason to focus
on real projects during your project
based learning plan as a you know on
autodidact you're making your own plan
making sure that those projects are as
close to the real thing as possible
because you're not going to get a sense
of whether you want to do it or not
unless it's a real project right so let
me give you an example so somebody I
really love tying contests right I love
doing those right does somebody do do
people like typ maybe somebody doesn't
like typ very much but they love to play
a typing game right so they might find
themselves really enjoying doing the
typing game but they're not really
getting a sense of whether they want to
do that every day because they're not
going to be typing in a typing game
every day they're going to be typing
whatever it is they're going to be doing
th this goes for websites it goes for
you know development of applications and
and that all of that sort of thing if
you I'm not against gamified
education but it's really important that
you don't make education too fun that
should probably be the the tagline
because gamified education while it does
make education more enjoyable um it's
not helping you identify the things that
you want to do every day uh in my
opinion the best gamification of
education is finding the exact thing
that you want to do on the job and
setting for
yourself uh you know a goal about
whether you're going to accomplish it
and how you're going to accomplish it
and imagining a real thing that you want
that is in your scope uh that you need
and then making that thing right uh and
that could be a game I mean for the
longest time we would learn how to make
a game to learn web development and
JavaScript and things like that and
that's 100% you know legit right you end
up with an actual game that people can
play that can become famous I have a
story about that I'll tell when we talk
about that so so Project based learning
is going to be more motivational it's
going to help the the learning stick
better and it's going to give something
for you to put in your resume right away
and so I'll conclude by saying that for
all of the beginner boost every single
thing we do is Project based that means
that when we talk about HTML or go or
bash or any of this that we are doing it
in the context of something that you we
assume you want to make and if as we're
making it if it turns out to not be
something that you want to make or you
you don't find a value in it then you've
already learned something about yourself
but maybe this is not for you this is
not your kind of thing so so that is the
importance of Project based learning and
as I'll say it again gamified learning
is good but it's even better when the
game is something that you've set out to
do for yourself and you're not
necessarily competing against others
you're competing against your own
yourself and your own how and you know
who you were yesterday